A Guide to the Winchester (Va.) Records, 1786-1979
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Winchester (Va.) Records, 1786-1979
Library of Virginia
1006070, 1013649, 1013650, 1017114, 1017115, 1017119, 1017121-1017124, 1096756, 1096834, 1140453-1140454
14 boxes
Winchester (Va.) Circuit Court
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in shipments of court papers from Winchester (Va.)
Biographical Information
The city of Winchester, in Frederick County, was first known as Opequon, then as Frederick's Town (or Fredericktown), and, finally, on establishment as a town in 1752, as Winchester. According to tradition, one of the town's founders, James Wood, named the town in honor of his birthplace in England. Winchester was incorporated as a town in 1779 and as a city in 1874.
Scope and Content
Winchester (Va.) Records, 1786-1979, includes miscellaneous records from the following series: Bonds,Commissions,Oaths; Business Records,Corporations,Partnerships; Clerks' Records; Court Records; Election Records; Fiduciary Records; Health and Medical Records; Land Records; Marriage Records and Vital Statistics; Military and Pension Records; Public Buildings and Grounds; Road and Bridge Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Treasurer; Wills.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Winchester Records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult "A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm."
See the Lost Records Localities Digital Collection available at Virginia Memory.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Winchester (Va.) Circuit Court.
Subjects:
Public records--Virginia--Winchester.
Genre and Form Terms:
Local government records--Virginia--Winchester.
Contents List
- Records, 1815-1950:
  Lis Pendens(1894-1895); Unrecorded Deeds(1800-1935); Oaths(1905, 1957); Factors Lien(1964), Mechanics Liens(1894-1950); Homestead Papers/List of Heirs(1815-1938)
- Records, 1786-1914 circa:
  Judgments, Commonwealth Causes, executions, bonds, promissory notes, vouchers, accounts, and other exhibits re: judgment suits; Jury Records: Petit Jury Ballots; Clerk's Records: List of writings admitted to record; Bonds,Commissions,Oaths; Tax and Fiscal Records: Ordinary Bonds; W.W. Sperry's Accounts; Wills: Will of Jacob Hoffman, 1845.
- Court Records; Tax and Fiscal Records, 1820-1900 circa:
  Warrants and Summons; Executions; Warrants; Delinquent Lands; Insolvent Papers
- Records, 1808-1957:
  Land Records: Deeds, Lis Pendens: Court Records: Criminal papers, Jury records, summons, court finance, warrants, affidavits, executions; Tax and Fiscal Records: Corporation claims, Insolvent papers, and miscellaneous; Fiduciary Records: Estate accounts. Justice of the Peace Records: Warrants; Bonds,Commissions,Oaths: Officials' Bonds; Miscellaneous Records: Power of Attorney, mechanics liens; Business Records,Corporations,Partnerships: Mount Hebron Cemetery Company Receipts, 1844 circa; Clerks' Records: Correspondence; Marriage Records and Vital Statistics: Birth Index Cards, 1850-1900 circa.
- Court Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Miscellaneous Records, 1825-1895
  License Returns, Delinquent Taxes, Bonds, Justice Reports, and Personal Papers of Richard L. Gray
- Marriage License Applications, Election Returns and Oaths, Inheritance Taxes and Settlements, 1872-1955:
- Records, 1786-1925 circa:
  Court Records: judgments, Commonwealth Causes, Peace and recognizance bonds; Inventories of ardent spirits in local pharmacies re: Prohibition; Clerks' Records; Public Buildings and Grounds; Tax and Fiscal Records; Bonds,Commissions,Oaths; Election Records; Military and Pension Records: militia draught, 1806; Revolutionary War claim, 1819. Unprocessed
- Records, 1850-1926 circa:
  Court Records: Clerks' Records, judgments, Commonwealth Causes, criminal records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Fiduciary Records; Election Records; Health and Medical Records: Lunacy Papers, 1906
- Records, 1864-1906:
  List of Conveyances, Death Register, Delinquent Lands, Insolvent Capitation and Property, Marriage Licenses
- Road Book; Town Plat Book; Insolvent Lots, 1871-1874; 1876; 1886:
- Record of Delinquent Taxes and Payments; Record of Marriage Bonds, 1790-1878:
  Record of Delinquent Taxes and Payments, 1875-1878 and Record of Marriage Bonds, 1790-1809
- Records, 1850-1900:
  Bonds,Commissions,Oaths; Court Records; Election Records; Fiduciary Records; Land Records; Miscellaneous Records; Military and Pension Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Treasurer. Includes some Circuit Court of Frederick County.
- Election Records; Miscellaneous Records, 1800-1900 circa:
  Election Records, Miscellaneous Records. Includes some Circuit Court of Frederick County.